Lucas Brown

Pipeline TD

Contact

Address

Georgetown TX

Phone

(747)-221-4849

E-mail

ImLucasBrown@gmail.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/imlucasbrown

Skills

Python

Maya (pymel, cmds, om)

Shotgrid (apps, automation, ect)

Rigging

Tech Anim

Pipeline TD with experience in full stack Python development, pipeline backend, rigging, Shotgrid automation, for product design, animation, games. Expandable and easily deployable systems are king. Motivated and excited to work with supervisors, artists, and programmers to create a well oiled, easy to use, CG pipeline.

Work History

2021-03 -Today

Pipeline TD

SGS & Co. - Thr3d CGI, Detroit MI (Remote)

- Directly supporting art and production staff.
- Develop and maintain a large library of Shotgrid apps.
- Designed and deployed scalable Shotgrid automation systems. Utilizing event daemons, webhooks, and AWS.
- Deadline farm wrangling, optimization, and debugging.
- Upgrading legacy Python 2 tools to Python 3.

2019-09 -2020-12

Pipeline TD

Sunrise Productions, Cape Town

- Lead full stack Python developer on "NXT" (<u>Node Execution Tree</u>). A visual, node base, layered, code compositing application. Utilized Qt framework. Developed RPC/IPC backend for linear code execution in multiple DCCs.
- Pipeline backend development. CLI tools for asset creation and Python entry points for front end devs to utilize in various user interfaces.
- Pixar USD research and integration

2017-11 -2019-05

Character Rigger

Pretty Simple Games, Paris, France

I developed rigs for characters, props, and vehicles to be used in a mobile game. On the pipeline side I took it upon myself to develop tools and workflows for the development of tools for asset creation/publishing.

On the animation side I developed tools for motion capture retargeting as well as easy QTE (Quick time event) creation and editing inside Maya.

Education

2013-01 -2017-05

Bachelor of Science: Animation

Southern Adventist University - Collegedale, TN

• Awarded "Excellence in Character Technical Direction"